<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>POST on feo</title>
    <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in POST on feo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Fatih Emre Ozturk</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 16:18:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization with Base R</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 16:18:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/dataviz/</guid>
      <description>Data visualization can be defined as the use of graphical or pictorial representations to present data in a way that makes it easier to understand, analyze, and communicate. It involves the use of visual elements such as charts, graphs, and maps to help users better understand and interpret complex data sets. Data visualization is an important tool for exploratory data analysis, as well as for communicating results to others. By presenting data in a visual format, data visualization can also help to reveal new connections and insights that might not be apparent from a purely numerical or textual analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logical Fallacies in Data Science (Part II)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/fallacies2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 19:25:30 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/fallacies2/</guid>
      <description>As a philosophy undergraduate and data science graduate student, I continue to share with you logical fallacies in data science in the second post of this series where I make the connection between Philosophy and Data Science.In the first post of this series, I examined three logical fallacies. In this post, I will examine five more fallacies.
Post Hoc Fallacy The post hoc fallacy is a common logical error that arises when individuals assume that just because one event follows another, it must have been caused by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Learning in R | k-medoids clustering</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/kmedoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 16:18:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/kmedoids/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post of this series, I covered how k-means clustering works in detail. In this post, I will try to explain the k-medoids algorithm, also known as Partitioning Around Medoids. First, I will explain what k-medoids is, then I will explain how it works step by step, and then I will explain how to implement it using the R program language.
What is k-medoids? k-medoids is a clustering algorithm that is similar to k-means, but instead of using the mean of the observations in each cluster as the centroid, it uses one of the observations in the cluster as the &amp;quot;medoid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Learning in R | k-means Clustering</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/kmeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 11:14:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/kmeans/</guid>
      <description>In the second post of the unsupervised statistical learning in R series, I will share with you the k-means clustering algorithm. I believe, at first, it is beneficial to define what clustering is, before explaining k-means clustering. Clustering can be defined as partitioning observation in a data set according to their similarity. We expect that observations in the same cluster to be similar as much as possible. Conversely, observations in the different clusters need to be dissimilar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logical Fallacies in Data Science</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/fallacies1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 09:37:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/fallacies1/</guid>
      <description>People are often surprised when they find out that I majored in philosophy as an undergraduate. They think that philosophy has nothing to do with the career I am trying to build in data science, or even that the technical knowledge required for data science would be insufficient.While I think they are quite reasonable in their skepticism, I think that philosophy education is very useful for learning data science. For this purpose, in this first post of this series, I will talk about some data science topics that are related to philosophy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infinite Monkey</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/infmonkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 23:06:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/infmonkey/</guid>
      <description>Living is the art of dealing with as many problems as there are solutions. For this reason, as long as we are alive, we constantly have to struggle with a number of problems.
There will always be problems, waiting to be solved. All we need to do is to try over and over again to overcome them. Just like Albert Einstein states:
&amp;quot;It&#39;s not that I&#39;m so smart, it&#39;s just that I stay with problems longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Learning in R | Determination of Cluster Number</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/kmethods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 19:49:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/post/kmethods/</guid>
      <description>I plan to write many series of articles in my medium journey that I started with data visualization. In addition to series such as Unsupervised Statistical Learning, Supervised Statistical Learning, Math for Data Science, Statistics and Probability, I will also touch on the intersection of my undergraduate degree in philosophy and data science. In this way, I think I can support analytical and critical thinking for the individual who is on a data science journey.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
